Francis Audric U. Ortiz Backend Developer

fauortiz@gmail.com github.com/fauortiz +63 9274736520 Rizal, Philippines

I had been working as an Industrial Engineer for 3 years when I realized I wanted to pursue a career in programming. I wanted to make things. I completed Harvard's CS50x, CS50W, and more, and I have since developed my portfolio. I am seeking the opportunity to improve through experience and learn how to code with a team, and I hope to bring a fresh perspective to the workplace.

PROJECTS

My Portfolio Site (https://francisortiz.netlify.app/)

Built using Next.js and Netlify. My featured projects are listed here, including those below.

SHIRISTORY: a word chain game (https://shiristory.herokuapp.com/)

A live demo of a game I designed, made using Django, SQL, React, and Heroku. Features user profiles, player progression, customizable abilities, and leaderboards.

E-commerce Site

Designed a CRUD app for a mock auction e-commerce site with Django and SQL.

Twitter-like App

Designed the API, database, and frontend for a mock social network app using JS, Django, and SQL.

SKILLS

Languages	Proficient in JavaScript, P	thon, SQL, HTML	, CSS. Dabbled in C. Willing to learn.
-----------	-----------------------------	-----------------	--

Technologies Proficient in React, Next.js, Django, Flask, SQLite, SASS, Bootstrap, Heroku, Netlify,

and Git. Familiar with jQuery, GitHub, Docker. Willing to learn.

Soft Skills Analysis, Critical Thinking, Problem Solving, Crisis Management, Project

Management, Teamwork, Team Management, Communication, Presentation.

EMPLOYMENT

2019 – 2020	Head of Supply Chain Excellence at The Standard Group
2019 – 2020	Senior Planner for Demand and Logistics at The Standard Group
2018 – 2019	Demand Planner at The Standard Group
2017 – 2018	Supply Planner for Meats and Commodities at The Standard Group

EDUCATION

2007 – 2011	Philippine Science High School – Main Campus
2011 – 2016	College of Engineering, University of the Philippines – Diliman BS Industrial Engineering – DOST-SEI Merit Scholarship Awardee
2020 – 2020	Harvard CS50 Introduction to Computer Science
2021 – 2022	Harvard CS50 Web Programming with Python and JavaScript